FABIO A NAVARRETE HIGUERA E-mail: fabioanh@gmail.com

Tel: +32 493169603

Location: Berlin, Germany

Brief Profile:



Software engineer born 1988 in Colombia. I enjoy solving scientific and technical problems and I'm eager to learn new things. Creativity is one of my main drivers, so I enjoy using the different skills I possess. I like to keep my interests diversified and I thrive developing software. I've been working professionally for around 9 years. Being part of multiple software teams in 5 different countries, I learnt a wide range of technologies. Java has kept me busy most of the time, but I also used Python and Kotlin in academic and personal projects. My strongest skills are related to the design and development of RESTful APIs. Currently I'm looking forward to taking my Kotlin skills to the level.

Academic Background:



Systems Engineer (Bachelor of Science) -Universidad Nacional de Colombia - 2010

Artificial Intelligence (Master studies) -Vrije Universiteit Brussel - Unfinished

Information Technology Tools:



Java 👙	Python 🦺	Linux
Spring 💋	Postgres 📭	Flutter
Hibernate 🗣	Oracle	TensorFlow
RESTful {}	Jira💠	JUnit
Git 🚸	JMeter /jMeter	Mockito
AWS aws	Jenkins 🧌	Kotlin
Solr	Google Cloud	2
MongoDB 🌗	Kubernetes 🛞	
Spring Boot (U		

Miscellaneous:

Interested in the study of complex systems and Artificial Intelligence. social simulations and Curious about anthropology. Amateur drums player. like to teach, and constantly improve my language skills. Fond of hiking and nature contemplation.

Job History:



ubitricity(Jun 2021 - Today Berlin)

Development of platform for charging point provider. Rest APT spring-boot microservices on Google Cloud. Scrum team.



IPlytics (Sept 2020 - May 2021 Berlin)

Intelectual property platform development. Web App using Spring Boot. Cloud migration, Azure Kubernetes. Data Engineering Spark + airflow.



Proximus (Feb 2018 - Jun 2019 Belgium) Web-shop development mostly involved with the Rest API. Scrum teams, project with around 30 people total.



Adneom (Jun 2016 - Dec 2017 Belgium)

Consultancy work for ENGIE: support during migration of web application backend from Java to Python. BPost: JEE app.



Advaita (Nov 2013 - Sep 2015 USA)

Development of a RESTful API using Spring, replacing a stalled desktop product for a bioinformatics start-



Globant (Jun 2012 - Oct 2013 Colombia)

JEE development. Worked on several applications for external clients. Additional tests automation tasks.



Spoken Languages:

English - C1 French - B2 German - A2 Italian - A2 Spanish - Native